# Michael Metry - Software Engineer

Markham, ON | (647)-937-4240 | LinkedIn | michaelmetry3@gmail.com

## **Objective**

I have completed my final year of Software Engineering at Ontario Tech University. My goals are to receive valuable and long-life experiences working with a software-based company. This would allow me to apply what I was taught in university and incorporate it into building and developing software products. Lastly, I am very confident in learning new concepts quickly and applying them to individually or group-based projects.

## **Experience**

#### Camp GA | Counselor

June 2022 - August 2022

- Engaged with children between 7-8 years of age with a variety of activities provided.
- Supervised children and provided a safe and friendly space.
- Demonstrated leadership, communication, and teamwork skills with co-workers.

#### **ASP Computers | Entry Volunteer**

June 2016 - June 2018

- Experienced working with hardware and software in building and configuring PCs.
- Handling customer service with the use of TeamViewer Application to resolve technical problems remotely.
- Developed an understanding of network configuration by incorporating with electronic devices

### **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering (Hons.), Software Engineering

September 2019 - April 2023

Ontario Tech University | Oshawa, ON

#### Skills

Languages: Python, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Microsoft SQL, C/C++, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Java, Flutter & Dart, PHP

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React/React.js, Next.js, Confluent Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, PyTest

<u>Tools & Technologies:</u> Android Studio, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, Visual Studio IDE, Atom IDE, PyCharm IDE, Apache Spark, IntelliJ IDEA, Git/GitHub, Codeblocks IDE, Linux, Firebase, SOLIDWORKS, AutoCAD, Jupyter

### **Licenses & Certifications**

• Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals

September 2023

October 2023

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

## **Projects**

#### Capstone Smart Blinds System (Python, Android Studio, Java, C/C++, JSON, Firebase Database)

- Designed using a mobile app to control lighting and temperature of a home.
- Arduino sensors were used to detect the level of light, temperature, and time values in a home.
- Incorporated Machine Learning libraries to let the blinds recognize and train data patterns to let the blinds automatically adjust, making your life effortless through user preferences.

#### Video Game Website (HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, WAMPSERVER)

- Incorporated the use of HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, and WAMPSERVER to design a web application game which involved avoiding obstacles falling from the sky and getting your character to the highest level possible
- The WAMPSERVER was used to record responses when users signs up on the website and leaving comments at the end of the game for possible improvements.